A Guide to the Thomas Fauntleroy Ball Papers 1902-1960
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Thomas Fauntleroy Ball Papers 1902-1960
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12711-b
This collection consists of ca. 200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was made a gift to the University on 1969 August 4 by Mrs. Thomas Fauntleroy Ball Willis.
Biographical/Historical Information
University of South Carolina, B.S., electrical engineering, University of Virginia, M.S.,1919; University of Virginia Instructor, Adjunct Professor and Assistant Professor of Physics, 1916-1922; also, taught at the University of South Carolina and headed the physics department, United States Naval Academy.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball including: articles; business correspondence; genealogical material regarding the Venable family; correspondence and papers dealing with cancer research at Johns Hopkins University; writings while at the University of South Carolina and Hughes Aircraft Company; testimonials for Samuel Reynolds Pritchard of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute; notes and notebooks; and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Article by Raynond J. Seeger 1959 (Box 1)
- Articles Written by Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1934-1956 (Box 1)
- Business Correspondence of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1930-1940 (Box 1)
- Business Correspondence of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1941-1960 (Box 1)
- Cancer Investigations at Johns Hopkins University: Appendices 1952 (Box 1)
- Cancer Investigations at Johns Hopkins University: Correspondence 1952 (Box 1)
- Cancer investigations at Johns Hopkins University: Miscellaneous Material 1952, 1955, n.d. (Box 1)
- Cancer Investigations at Johns Hopkins University: Proposal 1952 (Box 1)
  (2 copies)
- Genealogical Material re: Venable family 1902 (Box 1)
- An Introduction to Nuclear Physics by Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1957 (Box 1)
- Laboratory Experiments in Direct and Alternating Currents by Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1940 (Box 1)
- Material re: Samuel Reynolds Prichard 1929-1932 (Box 1)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Elements of Tensor Calculus: vol. 1-2" 1915-1916 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"'Principles of Elementary Statistical Mechanics,' by Josiah Willard Gibbs" 1917 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Dynamics--Physics" 1917 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Atomistics" 1924 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"The Classical Laws of Radiation" 1924 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Lectures in Physical Chemistry, by Debye: vol. 1-3" 1925 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Miscellaneous Lectures: vol. 1-4" 1924 (Box 2)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Collidal Chemistry Applied to Geology" n.d. (Box 3)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--" God and Man at Yale, William F. Buckley, Jr." ca. 1950-1951 (Box 3)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"Theory of Relativity: vol. 1-3" n.d. (Box 3)
- Notebook of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball--"(1) Lectures; (2) Problems in Thermodynamics" n.d. (Box 3)
- Notes of Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1929, n.d. (Box 3)
- Personal Papers 1941 (Box 3)
- Printed Material 1931-1952, n.d. (Box 3)
- The Public and Its Utilities by Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1931 (Box 3)
- "Some Facts About Public Utilities," a collection of articles, by Thomas Fauntleroy Ball 1938 (Box 3)